Andrew Forster

Field Engineer - Pall Corporation

West Chester, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Andrew-Forster/825e8e0f73e757bc

I am an experienced Field Engineer with nine years of experience in several lines of business including; microelectronics, polymer and injection molding, food and beverage, biopharmaceutical, fuels and chemicals, water treatment, and power generation. I have am continually working as part of a team and individually depending on the project requirements. I always strive for the highest quality toward the achievement of common goals. I have been recognized for a great combination of engineering skill along with sales and marketing expertise. I am accustomed to communicating with and supporting all levels and different types of stakeholders. I am capable of nurturing a culture that defines a growing and learning organization with emphasis on enhancing the bottom-line. Proficient with Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint, and Excel), CAD, MicroStation, SAP, and Lotus Notes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Field Engineer

Pall Corporation - Exton, PA - 2006 to Present

Offer in-field support and guidance on daily challenges related to initial development, pilot testing, plant surveys and consultations, troubleshooting and problem solving, demonstrations, and personnel training.

- Prepare and analyze data from laboratory and full scale testing.
- Develop side stream and pilot trials, within customer specifications, to determine proper sizing and classifications of filtration equipment.
- Develop and design testing equipment to be utilized in customer related trials and process validation.
- Facilitate extensive customer training regarding standard maintenance and operation of equipment.
- Administer and maintain a smooth workflow of internal diagnostic and repair facilities including stocking of spare parts and pursuing regularly scheduled preventive maintenance.
- Display troubleshooting expertise and customer technical support.
- Design and implement systems including pumps, filters, pressure vessels, valves, and heat exchangers.
- Design new systems for customers using CAD and performing on site alterations.
- Oversee customer complaints on product quality, including product failure investigations, internal and external corrective action, root cause analysis, and preventative action implementation.
- Coordinate with manufacturing engineers, globally, to troubleshoot and solve quality issues.
- Lead in process improvement team to continually increase efficiencies of quality investigations and productivity.
- Traveling sales representative for select customer base. Providing quotations, sales and technical support, and calculating quarterly sales volumes. Identify opportunity to grow customer sales.

Consulting Intern

Artex Knitting Co - Dresher, PA - 2005 to 2006

Expertly handled all aspects of troubleshooting, repairing, and redesigning company equipment.

Engineering Intern

Middle River Aircraft Systems - Middle River, MD - 2005 to 2005

2005

- Served as manufacturing engineer, responsible for material supply and quality control maintenance as well as tool and machinery maintenance.
- Functioned well as industrial engineer, overseeing cost analysis, cost reduction, and manufacturing efficiency.
- Key member on process improvement team to increase production efficiencies on product manufacturing line.

SALES

SALES Salesman

True Value Hardware - Wayne, PA - 1998 to 2001

Participated in and completed effective training regarding register and key cutter.

- Managed and executed various functions, such as bookkeeping and billing.
- Rendered exceptional assistance to all incoming customers in the store.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering Minor in Material Science

University of Delaware - Newark, DE 2006

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

CORE COMPETENCIES

Sales and Marketing
Coordination and Collaboration
Project Development and Management
Equipment Maintenance and Troubleshooting
Public Speaking and Presentation
Strategic Planning and Implementation